( ALARM BUZZING )
( BANGING )
( CREAKING )
( ALARM STOPS )
( DOOR CREAKING )
So it 's 6 : 00 p.m. in the nighttime , which is when I wake up .
This is always really scary part for me .
Yes ! Nighttime .
So , now I 'm going to wake up my flatmates .
I really love living in a flatting situation .
Wake up ! Wake up , everyone !
I like to hang out with other vampires .
I like the company .
Awaken !
Awakey-wakey !
I just really like having a good time with my friends .
Deacon , hi !
Hey , Deacon .
( HISSING )
How was your night , last night ?
I transformed into a dog and had sex .
Cool !
We 're gonna have a little flat meeting in the kitchen
in about 15 minutes , okay ?
- Okay . - Okay .
- Should I close this ? - Yes .
( KNOCKING )
Vladislav ?
- ( WOMAN MOANING ) - Oh !
( SNARLING )
Sorry ! Sorry !
What ?
- Hey . - What time is it ?
Um ... We 're going to have a flat meeting in about 10 minutes .
Twenty .
Okay . Is there ...
( CLUCKING )
( WHISPERING ) So , we 're in Petyr 's room .
I 'm just going to wake him up .
( GRUNTING )
Petyr ?
Petyr , wake up .
( SNARLS )
Hey , listen .
We 're just having a flat meeting upstairs in about 10 minutes .
You don 't have to come ,
but I thought I 'd extend an invitation to you just in case .
Um ...
There 's a lot of stuff on the floor down here , Petyr .
Like this , it seems ... I don 't ...
Oh , it 's a spinal column . Yuck .
And I was thinking ,
maybe I should just bring a broom down here for you
if you wanted to sweep up some of the skeletons .
I don 't know . You know , maybe ...
( SNARLING )
Okay .
I got you this chicken .
( CLUCKING )
Is Petyr coming ?
Should we be worried ?
Petyr 's 8,000 years old .
We 're not going to have Petyr at the meeting .
Okay , so I wanted to have a quick chat
about flat responsibilities
because , guys , I think that we 're not all pulling our weight here .
We 're not just pointing the finger at you , Deacon .
You 're a cool guy , but you 're not
pulling your weight in the flat .
Well , I 'm glad to hear that I 'm cool . ( CHUCKLES )
No , that 's not the point though .
- You missed it . - No , I know , I know .
Yeah , it 's not a flat meeting about how cool you are .
DEACON : I do my flat chores .
- No , you don 't ! - Yes , I do .
No , you don 't . This is why we 're having the flat meeting .
The point is , Deacon ,
that you have not done the dishes for five years .
Vladislav is right .
It 's unacceptable to have so many bloody dishes
all over this bench like that .
I 'm so embarrassed when people come over here .
What does it matter ? You bring them over , you kill them !
Yeah .
Vampires don 't do dishes .
VIAGO : Deacon 's like the rebellious young vampire .
He 's always doing crazy things , saying crazy things .
He 's just like the young bad boy of the group .
Okay , so
one day I was selling my wares ,
and I walked past this old creepy castle ,
and I look at it and think ,
" Very old and creepy . "
And then this creature flies at me .
It dragged me back to this dark dungeon
and bit into my neck .
And just at the point of death ,
this creature forced me to suck its foul blood ,
and then it opened its wings like this
and hovered above me , screeching ,
( MIMICS SCREECHING )
( IN RASPY TONE ) " Now you are vampire . "
And it was Petyr .
And we 're still friends today .
Vlad , you were great .
You put out the recycling , which was really cool .
And the other day , I dragged a man 's body down the hallway
and noticed that there was no dust .
Like , I kind of ... I kind of swept the hallway .
VIAGO : Vladislav is just like this older vampire
who grew up in the medieval times .
And to be living this long
and to have seen the things that he 's seen
( EXCLAIMS )
and still kind of have it together ...
Ow !
I mean , hats off to him .
Bloody hell !
Sorry !
VIAGO : He 's a really great guy .
A bit of a pervert .
He has some pretty old ideas about things .
- But we should get some slaves . - Yes .
VLADISLAV : When I first became a vampire ,
I was quite tyrannical .
I was known for , uh , torturing a lot of people .
This is my torture chamber .
I don 't come in here often anymore .
I tended to torture when I was in a bad place .
My thing was I would poke someone with implements .
I was known as Vladislav the Poker .
It 's been like this the whole time , okay ?
DEACON : Viago is a little pedantic .
The washing and the rubbish , I did that .
Deacon , on dishes , and it 's still hasn 't moved in five years .
He was an 18th century dandy ,
so he can be very fussy .
He nags and nags .
... went in the lounge the other day ,
and there was blood all over my nice antique couch .
Which one , the red one ?
Well , it 's red now , yeah .
If you 're going to eat a victim on my nice clean couch ,
put down some newspaper on the floor and some towels .
It 's not hard to do .
We 're vampires . We don 't put down towels .
Some vampires do .
Well , not serious ones .
VLADISLAV : When you get four vampires in a flat ,
obviously there 's going to be a lot of tension .
There 's tension in any flatting situation .
It 's settled then . We 'll all do our jobs ,
starting with a certain Deacon ...
I will do my dishes !
Good , then do them !
( HISSING )
This is bullshit .
( VACUUM HUMMING )
I became a vampire when I was 16 ,
and that is why I always look 16 .
In those days , of course ,
life was tough for a 16-year-old .
VIAGO : Vampires have had a pretty bad rep .
We 're not these mopey old creatures who live in castles .
Well , some ... Most of us are . A lot are .
But there are also those of us
who like to flat together
in really small countries , like New Zealand .
I was a Nazi vampire .
( HITLER SPEAKING IN GERMAN )
DEACON : After the war , which the Nazis lost ...
I don 't know if you know that the Nazis lost that war .
If you were a Nazi , after the war ...
And if you were a vampire ...
And if you were a Nazi vampire ,
no way .
I was out of there .
Ja , I came to this country for love .
Uh ... There was a girl , human girl ,
and I thought she was fantastic .
She was absolutely amazing .
I was smitten .
Her family emigrated to New Zealand .
And I thought ,
" You know what ? To hell with it . I 'm going to go .
" I 'm going to chase her and tell her how I feel . "
I told my servant Phillip ,
- " Send me to New Zealand . " - ( SHIP 'S HORN BLOWING )
He put the wrong postage on my coffin ,
so the whole journey took about 18 months .
And when I got here , she had found someone else .
She had fallen in love
and she was married .
She gave me this before she left .
There she is .
That 's me . I put myself in there , too .
She told me it was pure silver .
Unfortunately , we vampires cannot wear silver .
( SIZZLING )
( GASPING PAINFULLY )
( WHIMPERING )
( BLOWING RAPIDLY )
Yeah .
That 's about as long as I can wear that .
( TRUMPET BLOWING )
( ALL PLAYING OFF-KEY )
VLADISLAV : Tonight , we are going out into Wellington Central .
It is important that we look good .
Yeah , it 's really good , yeah . Like it .
One of the unfortunate things about not having a reflection
is that you don 't know exactly what you look like .
Whoo !
Look , a ghost cup floating all by itself .
VLADISLAV : We can give each other feedback
and help each other out until we 're looking great .
VIAGO : Yes , some of our clothes are from victims .
You might bite someone and then
you think , " Ooh , those are some nice pants . "
- Should I wear these ? - No . Change it .
When you are a vampire , you become very sexy .
VLADISLAV : We are trying to attract victims to us .
Not sure about the waistcoat .
I go for a look which I call , " Dead But Delicious . "
VLADISLAV : We are the bait , but we are also the trap .
Hello , ladies . ( CHUCKLES )
And voila , we are ready to go into town and party ...
ALL : Vampire style .
DEACON : When we go into town , we must try to blend in .
DEACON : Just walking the streets .
Coming into town , um , is really cool
because just for one brief moment ,
- I feel ... - MAN : Homos !
The trouble with being a vampire
is you have to be invited in to go in .
DEACON : We 'd like to come into the bar , please .
Can you invite us into the bar , please ?
$ 5 , you can walk in .
Will you invite us in ?
VLADISLAV : If the humans found out what we were , they would destroy us .
VIAGO : There are between 60 and 70 vampires
- in the Greater Wellington region . - ( HISSING )
VLADISLAV : Obvious vampire .
- VIAGO : Julie . - Hello .
- How embarrassing . - ( VIAGO LAUGHING )
He 's a guy I used to work with , when I was human .
- Before , when I was human . - Gone ?
Yeah , he 's gone . I 've been draining him all night . ( CHUCKLES )
I 've been a very thirsty girl .
VLADISLAV : Hey , guys .
VIAGO : Being bitten as a little boy or a little girl ,
you 're always going to look the same age .
VLADISLAV : What are you doing tonight ?
Are you going to kill some perverts ?
CHILD : Yeah , we 're meeting a pedophile .
- Cool . - CHILD : Yeah .
Okay . Let 's just go to Big Kumara .
- BOUNCER : Have a good night , guys . - Yeah . You , too . Bye .
Big Kumara is vampire-owned and operated ,
and so we can always get in .
It 's the hottest night spot for vampires in Wellington .
Come on in , guys . Come on in .
- Thank you . Thanks . - Thank you .
( MUSIC PLAYING )
Perhaps you could bring some people to the house .
- Sure . - Perhaps some virgins ?
Virgins ? Yep , okay .
Any kind of preference in terms of gender or ...
Maybe some ladies ?
Yep , ladies .
Perhaps a guy .
One of each ?
One of each should be cool .
JACKIE : My relationship with Deacon is ...
Well , I 'm his familiar . He 's my master .
He tells me what to do , I do it .
We have that kind of master-servant relationship ,
which works nicely , actually .
JACKIE : Hello . DRY CLEANER : Hello .
It 's a little bit of blood .
- Um ... My husband , he 's a hemophiliac . - Okay .
You know , someone that bleeds a lot .
Yeah .
JACKIE : Any kind of age range ?
DEACON : Young .
But not kids ?
Not kids .
18 to 30 ?
Definitely younger than yourself .
Okay . So , 18 to 30 .
- So , it 's a dinner party . - Great .
- I 'll be there . You 'll be there . - Yes , dinner party .
The guys 'll be there . We 'll all be there .
Yes , we will dress up .
- Okay , great . - And then eat them .
- Okay . Great . - Should be fun .
I was just wondering if we could talk about the ...
Do you know of a night dentist ?
Because I have this thing here .
I was just wondering if we could talk about the deal .
- Hmm ? - The deal .
The dishes ?
No , you know , the deal .
The deal is that he is going to give me eternal life ,
um , which is
very exciting .
Well , I just feel like I 've kind of reached my potential ,
and I wouldn 't want to kind of get any older before ...
I just feel like I 'm the best version of myself that I can be .
It 's just that it 's been four and a half years , and I just ...
But it 's doing your pot plants ,
I 'm doing your dry cleaning ,
I 'm now doing your dishes , and I 'm doing ...
- I 'm just wondering ... - And the dentist .
- And the dentist . - The dentist .
And it 's just taking an awful long time .
- So I was just wondering if I ... - Be gone !
Okay .
- DEACON : See you later . - Okay .
( SCREAMING )
VIAGO : One of the most unfortunate things
about being a vampire is that
you have to drink human blood .
I like to make a real evening of it .
It 's lovely .
VIAGO : Play some music ,
maybe give them some nice wine .
It 's their last moment alive ,
so why not make it a nice experience ?
So , tell me what you do . What do you ...
WOMAN : I 'm thinking about going to uni , actually .
Oh , you are ? Let 's put this over there .
University , ja ?
Yeah , but after that I 'm gonna travel .
Yeah , really wanted to go overseas for ages .
So I 'm saving up , and I 'm gonna go
to Spain and Italy and London and ...
Yeah .
Okay . Excuse me . Just put that there .
Here we go .
( CHUCKLES SOFTLY )
- ( GASPS ) - ( SLOSHING )
Shit ! Shit !
( SPITS )
VIAGO : Well , that didn 't go so great .
Um ... I hit the main artery .
So , yeah , it 's a real mess in there .
Um ...
On the upside , I think she had a really good time .
( MICROPHONE RUSTLING )
So it 's quite late ,
and I 've managed to find a woman up watching television .
And she seems like she 'd be a good victim .
I 'm just going to use hypnosis on her .
See me .
She can 't see me from that angle .
VIAGO : Vladislav used to be extremely powerful .
He could hypnotize crowds of people .
DEACON : Great orgies . 20 , 30 women .
VIAGO : He could turn into all sorts of animals ,
but now he never get the faces right .
DEACON : He would kill anybody . Men , women , children .
Burning everything . It was totally great .
But he suffered a humiliating defeat
at the hands of his arch nemesis ,
The Beast .
And he 's never been the same .
See me .
Would you like to come inside ?
Mmm . Mmm .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
- Oh ! - Ah !
Jackie , welcome !
- Hello . - Come in .
This is Nick . Ex-ex-boyfriend .
- And Josephine . - Nice house .
And this is Deacon , my overseas friend from Europe .
JACKIE : Deacon and his friends need victims .
VIAGO : Hi . Please come in . Welcome .
They can 't be people
that I actually invest in or like
because , of course , they will become victims .
Hi , Josephine ?
No , I sat next to you in English . Remember ?
Um ... Uh , you used to call me the Jaxocist .
No , you did . No , you did . Yeah .
No , you started that .
You were the one that started calling me that ,
and then everyone ... Then it kind of caught on . Yeah .
( LAUGHING ) Okay , bye then . Bye .
She 's in .
( INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
Do you like that , Nick ?
Yup . Good choice .
I will go and prepare dinner .
Please .
Nick , are you a virgin at all ?
Ah , what ?
VLADISLAV : Doesn 't seem like ... Are you a virgin ?
Ah , yes .
Um ... No .
You were a virgin when we were seeing each other ?
Yeah , I was 12 .
DEACON : You said he was a virgin .
I think we drink virgin blood because it sounds cool .
VLADISLAV : I think of it like this .
If you 're going to eat a sandwich ,
you would just enjoy it more
if you knew no one had fucked it .
DEACON : Let 's concentrate on Josephine then .
Are you a virgin ?
JOSEPHINE : ( CLEARS THROAT ) I 'm not , no .
Okay , I 'm really sorry
because I totally pinned her as a virgin .
She looks like a virgin , she talks like a virgin . I mean ...
Who would have sex with her ? I wouldn 't .
I would .
Oh .
Thank you .
Okay , there 's two dinners .
- Yum . - DEACON : Nick .
Do you like biz-ghetti ?
NICK : Uh ... Yep . Usually like it .
But be better if it was warm .
DEACON : So this is my favorite trick .
We present our guest with a plate of biz-ghetti .
And then I will say , " Why don 't you eat some biz-ghetti ? "
Please , Nick , eat some biz-ghetti .
I didn 't realize you enjoyed eating worms , Nick .
- No . No . - DEACON : They are worms .
( LAUGHING )
There 's worms wriggling around on my plate .
VLADISLAV : It is wormlike , but not actually worms .
This is merely biz-ghetti .
DEACON : We stole that idea from The Lost Boys .
But I put a nice twist on it .
Nick , how did it feel
to have a snake for a penis ?
( LAUGHING )
NICK : Jackie , my penis has disappeared . There 's a cobra snake .
- DEACON : Penis trick . - No one 's gonna mistake your penis
for a cobra , Nick , okay ?
- Believe you me . - What did you put in my spaghetti ?
No , it is just a normal penis .
I 'm out . I 'm out .
Josephine , do you like biz-ghetti ?
Look , these freaks spike my spaghetti ,
make my cock turn into a snake .
This is not cool . Not cool .
You don 't think this is weird ?
For fuck 's sakes .
( CAR LOCK BEEPS )
Jackie !
- Jackie ! - ( BANGING )
Sorry , Nick .
What are you doing ?
Jackie !
( SNARLING )
Shit ! Shit !
( SCREECHING )
What the fuck ?
Nah . Nah .
( SNARLING )
( DOOR RATTLING )
Fuck off .
( SILENCE )
NICK : Where am I ?
( HISSING )
( NICK GRUNTS )
( GROWLS )
( ALL HISSING )
Fuck .
Fuck !
( GRUNTS )
( GIGGLING )
Freaks !
( SNARLING )
Oh , no , Petyr got him .
VLADISLAV : Poor guy .
DEACON : Who let Petyr out ?
( BAGPIPES PLAYING )
( FOLK MUSIC PLAYING )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
NICK : Hey , guys !
Hey , what are you guys doing ?
VLADISLAV : What are you doing , Nick ?
DEACON : Come into the house .
- Hi , my name is Nick . - Hey , guys . What are you up to ?
I 've been a vampire for two months .
Probably , I reckon the best thing about being a vampire is flying .
Like I 've always wanted to ...
I think everyone has always wanted to fly ,
and now I can do it .
( NICK GRUNTS )
Nick , why don 't you use the front door ?
Why would I ? I 'm flying .
NICK : Petyr bit me ,
sucked all my blood out .
I woke up in his basement , and he offered me some blood .
I just thought it was something ,
some German thing that these guys do .
This transition into becoming a vampire was pretty hard .
I looked like shit to start off with .
I had a massive gash in my neck .
You could see the inside of my neck .
I had blood all over my top .
And then I came home , and I was sweating .
I was either really hot or really cold .
It was like a hangover times 10 , I reckon . It was really bad .
- ( SCREAMING ) - It was quite similar to having the flu ,
except the only difference would probably be
( BONES CRACKING )
that my eyes bleed heaps .
Are you guys not cold ?
NICK : I don 't know , I can 't explain it .
It was just ... Yeah , just real hot and cold
and bloody eyes and flying and stuff .
DEACON : The neighbors can see you flying around the house .
You want to draw attention to this house , hmm ?
You 've got a whole documentary crew following you around .
I am doing an erotic dance for my friends ,
and you ruined it .
I was in the zone .
My friends were loving it .
I love it . I saw the end of it . It looked great .
NICK : I don 't know if I 'm being ... If I 'm accepted yet .
But , I don 't know , I think it 's getting there .
I know they 're old and stuff , but they 're quite naive
when it comes to the real world .
So , I don 't know , it 'll be cool to just hang out with them .
They can teach me some stuff .
I can probably teach them a few things .
( SCRATCHING )
( FOLK MUSIC PLAYING )
NICK : At the start it was like , " Oh , no , I 'm dead . "
It 's kind of affected my friendship
with normal people , my family and stuff .
But the way I see it , I 've got a whole new family .
They accept me for who I am ,
and I accept them for who they are .
( VOCALIZING )
Even though one of them killed me .
VLADISLAV : Where should we go tonight ?
Let 's go to The Big Kumara .
NICK : Why don 't we go to Boogie Wonderland ?
VLADISLAV : We never get into Boogie Wonderland .
No . My friend Richie is the bouncer . He can get us in .
VIAGO : What ? Really ? NICK : He 'll invite us in .
Stu is keen . Stu loves it .
VIAGO : Who ? Is that Stu ?
Uh , this is my friend Stu .
- Hey . - Hey .
NICK : He works in computers and stuff .
Originally , he went out with my sister ,
and then they broke up .
I didn 't really get into it .
It 's got nothing to do with me . And ...
You can 't hear me .
All right . So , basically ,
Stu doesn 't know that I 'm a vampire ,
and he doesn 't know that my friends are vampires .
He just thinks that I 've just met some colorful friends .
This is jasmine .
NICK : I brought him round to the house ,
and they all thought I 'd brought a meal for everyone .
It just really , really sucks that I can 't eat him .
I just want to ... Ah !
Look at it . He 's the reddest guy I know .
All right . You can hear me .
You like computer-based stuff , mainly ?
- Yeah . Geo databases . - Yeah .
Yeah . Computers mainly .
Let 's have a vote . For Boogie Wonderland or The Big Kumara .
Big Kumara .
- Right . - Great .
NICK : Careful , Stu . Hurry up .
DEACON : I don 't think Nick should have been turned into a vampire .
He 's such a dick .
BOUNCER : How are you , brother ? Looking great , man .
Gentlemen , you are most welcome . ( LAUGHS )
( LOUD DANCE MUSIC PLAYING )
We 're in Boogie Wonderland !
So here we are at Boogie Wonderland ,
and it is so much fun .
They have an electric floor .
VIAGO : This is amazing !
I 'm just so happy to be here .
DEACON : This place is pretty cheesy .
Also , did you see the jacket he wore ?
He 's wearing the same jacket as me .
Not exactly the same . It 's ...
It 's pretty close .
NICK : What ? Of course not .
I 'm just loving being a vampire at the moment .
( ALL CHEERING AND SHOUTING )
( SCREAMING )
NICK : There 's the Fat Ladies Arms ,
on Wednesdays they do a Fear Factor competition .
You can win T-shirts and hats and spot prizes .
( SNIFFING )
I can smell werewolves .
VLADISLAV : We 're just about to walk past some werewolves ,
so some shit might go down .
DEACON : Look out , guys . Don 't catch fleas .
ANTON : What 's that , mate ? VIAGO : Deacon .
- Sorry , what ? - Keep going , keep walking .
ANTON : What ? We heard that , mate . We 've got sensitive hearing .
- DEACON : Have you ? - Yeah .
What are you filming ? Is it a music video , is it ?
We don 't want any trouble .
Well , then why did you start it then ?
I do . Have I got your heckles up , huh ?
Why don 't you go smell your own crotches , huh ?
- Come on , Deacon . Stop it . - What are you talking about ?
We don 't smell our own crotches .
We smell each other 's crotches .
And it 's a form of greeting .
You 're on camera , mate . Don 't ... Don 't do it .
- What ? - It 's okay , ' cause I know this guy .
It 's Count Fagula .
( MEN LAUGHING )
ANTON : Hey , hey , hey . Don 't swear .
Sorry , they ...
Yeah ? We 're werewolves , not swear-wolves .
What are we ?
ALL : Werewolves not swear-wolves .
- " Faggot " is not a swear word . - ANTON : No .
That 's a very offensive word to call people .
It 's offensive , but is it a swear word ?
Well , unless you 're talking about a bundle of sticks .
Chase this bundle of sticks , werewolves .
CLIFTON : No , no , no . It 's not real . It 's just ...
Don 't get it ! Nathan , it 's not real .
- He 's just going to take off his gloves . - All right .
Oh ! Shit , man . What the fuck did you do that for ?
Hey ! Don 't swear . We 're gonna lose it . We 're gonna lose it .
( SNARLING )
ANTON : Whoa , whoa , whoa ! Hey , calm down .
- Calm down . Dion . Dion . - Shit , I 've still got my glasses .
- Oh ! Oh ! Oh ! - Hey , hey .
( GROWLING )
Do the breathing . Do the breathing .
Okay . Do the breathing .
Count to 10 , mate . That 's all right . Come on .
- Count to 10 , human again . - Hold it .
Count to 10 , human again .
- Count to 10 , human again . - ( SNARLING )
It 's all right . It 's not a full moon .
Thanks a lot , guys . Enjoy your night . Yeah .
Should be ashamed of yourselves , man .
Great . We didn 't want this to happen .
( HISSING )
( ALL HOWLING )
ANTON : Come on , guys .
CLIFTON : Hey , say it , don 't spray it , bitch .
ANTON : Clifton !
Why are you swearing all the time ?
CLIFTON : Well , he riled me up .
- Were they actually werewolves ? - VIAGO : Ja .
Are you okay , Stu ?
NICK : I just don 't really know how to approach this ,
' cause I 've never done it before .
Um ... And he is a good friend , and I don 't want to ...
I don 't want to break that friendship .
But , then again , what do you do
when someone tells you that they 're a vampire ?
I 'm expecting him to be angry . He might be scared .
I 'm expecting a lot of things to bubble to the surface .
You probably notice there 's been ...
I 've been going through a few changes lately .
- Yeah . Yeah . - Yeah ?
Like I don 't show up for lunch anymore .
Yeah .
And how I 've changed all our tennis games
to nighttime tennis games .
Right .
And how you went from beating me every time ,
and now how I 've won the last three ?
STU : Yeah .
So , the reason I brought you here
is to tell you that I 'm a vampire .
NICK : Stu took it pretty well .
He 's definitely my best mate , and I 'm not gonna eat him .
If they ever offer you spaghetti , um ,
you shouldn 't eat it .
I think they offered me biscotti .
Vampire mates don 't eat human mates .
And no matter how much I wanted to eat him ,
I 'll never eat him because he 's my mate .
Eh , Stu ?
Yeah .
VIAGO : Stu is great .
We really like him .
At first I wanted to kill him ,
but now I 'm glad I spent the time to get to know him .
VIAGO : Ja , of course he looks delicious , with his big red cheeks .
But we 've all got an agreement
that we 're not going to eat Stu .
- Right ? - Right .
The guys upstairs , they 're loving him .
At the start they were a bit ,
" Who is this human you 're bringing into the house ? "
But it took them literally two minutes ,
and they like him more than they like me , I reckon .
I am knitting a scarf for Stu .
- Try and attack . Use your legs . - Okay .
( GRUNTING )
Wow !
- Step back , and block ... - Okay .
And punching high . Yep .
- Hi . - Yep .
I 'm just ... What I 'm trying to say is ,
' cause I know that you ...
You turned me into a vampire .
Maybe don 't do that to him .
He 's a vegetarian .
The last thing he 'd want to do is eat a live being ,
or eat blood , or eat meat .
( GRUNTS )
VIAGO : I am controlling this . DEACON : Get it . Get it .
VIAGO : It 's quite amazing to see
how far technology can go forward
if you 're not paying attention .
( CELL PHONE BEEPING )
" One message received . "
Oh !
( LAUGHING )
DEACON : " There is a crucifix behind you . "
So , down on that one .
Halfway down will focus it .
- ( CAMERA BEEPS ) - STU : Maybe smile .
- Anything you want to find , you ... - Yeah .
- You can type in ... - You write it into this .
I had lost a really nice silk scarf in about 1912 .
Yes , now Google it .
VLADISLAV : Stu is the first human friend that I 've had for a long time .
With humans , there 's a tendency to die .
Yeah .
STU : We can look at her photos .
- Oh , yes . - Or we could poke her .
Yes .
DEACON : Can we see a movie of a sunrise ?
( UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING )
Oh shit .
VLADISLAV : Ooh ! Nice .
If we push " Images , " then we can see pictures of virgins .
- Ja , ja , ja . - Yes .
VIAGO : No , go back . Go back .
VLADISLAV : I don 't think she 's a virgin if she 's doing that .
( CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( SCRATCHING )
VIAGO : There he is , yeah . This is my old servant , Phillip .
So we 're gonna call him .
Ja .
( LINE RINGING )
And maximize the screen .
( COMPUTER BEEPS )
VIAGO : My God , that 's him . That 's him . That 's him .
That 's Phillip . That 's Phillip . He looks so old .
( SPEAKING IN GERMAN )
( GRIMACES )
STU : Just click that . Yeah , that one .
... data about where things are .
Oh , like , Google Maps stuff ?
Yeah , kind of like Google Maps ,
but more layers of information .
The movie Twilight . Have you seen it ?
Yeah .
Okay , I 'm the main guy in Twilight .
You know the main guy ? Twilight ?
That 's me .
NICK : There 's cameras following me around .
They could 've chosen anyone .
How many people have you told you are a vampire ?
Not many .
I heard that girl talking about it .
She said you 're a vampire .
Yeah , I told her .
- VIAGO : Who else ? - Who did you tell ?
Uh ... I told her hot friend .
You can 't tell everyone that you 're
( WHISPERING ) a vampire .
VIAGO : Who is that guy ?
- I don 't know , but I trust him . - ( SCOFFS ) Oh !
- Keep it under your hat . - You can 't tell everyone .
All right , I won 't .
I 'm a vampire !
( ALL CHEERING )
Vampire !
Yeah , got a bit of a eye condition .
What 's wrong with them ?
Uh , vampire eyes . Can 't go into the sun .
Oh , my God , are they your fangs ? For real ?
For real real . It 's too real real .
I 'm a vampire , though .
- You 're a vampire ? - Yeah .
I 'm a vampire hunter , man .
( LAUGHS ) No , you 're not .
- I am . - Fuck you , piece of shit .
I 'll Skype you .
I can float . I can transform into stuff .
Same .
No , you can 't .
Yeah . I 'll show you .
You show me . Show me some of your vampire stuff .
What have I got ? Um ...
( HISSING )
Don 't lie about transforming into shit .
Twilight !
Shut up , Nick !
You 're not Twilight .
- What 's your problem ? - You are my problem .
Telling the world that we are vampires .
And I 'll tell the whole world
that you 're an asshole now , as well .
Shut up !
- You shut up ! - VIAGO : Guys ...
- You shut up ! - No , you shut up !
- No , you shut up . - You shut up .
I 'm Dracula , man !
- You 're not Dracula ! - I 'm Dracula , man !
You don 't even know who Dracula is , you idiot !
( BAT SCREECHING )
- Ooh ! Bat fight ! - Bat fight !
( ALL LAUGHING )
( DEACON GRUNTS )
( BAT SCREECHING )
( CLANGING )
VLADISLAV : Oh , Deacon !
That wasn 't fair , man .
My fuckin ' jacket , man .
DEACON : I don 't care about your stupid jacket .
- VIAGO : Deacon ! - ( BAT SCREECHING )
STU : Are you okay , mate ?
- Hey , Stu ? - Mmm-hmm ?
How 's your worms ?
What ?
You 're eating worms .
Can you do that shit where you turn it into worms ?
No , it ...
Doesn 't work on chips .
Only works on things
that already look like worms .
VLADISLAV : Maybe noodles . Do you want some noodles ?
But he knows now .
Oh , no , I wouldn 't eat that .
Why ?
( NICK VOMITING )
VLADISLAV : Are you okay , Nick ?
( GRUNTS )
All right ?
( VOMITING )
He ate a chip .
I can 't eat salads now . Great .
What , I can 't sunbathe . I can 't watch daytime TV .
I can if I ... Yeah , I guess I could .
More than anything it 's just the chips .
It 's my favorite food . I can 't eat chips .
This is ... I don 't ... It 's just I hate ...
I 'll say it . I 'm over being a vampire . It 's shit .
So , don 't believe the hype .
- ( ZAPPING ) - ( BAT SCREECHING )
- ( THUDDING ) - ( CAR ALARM BLARING )
Jackie !
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
DEACON : Jackie , can I come in , please ?
JACKIE : Okay , off to bed , guys .
DEACON : Hello , children .
JACKIE : Don 't look at the man . DEACON : Hey , little killdies .
JACKIE : Natasha , don 't look at the man .
I was going to bite you tonight .
Really ?
But now I can 't because there 's this Nick being a vampire .
Sorry , I thought you killed him two months ago , didn 't you ?
No , I didn 't . No , he 's a vampire .
What do you mean ?
He jumped in front of your place .
All I 'm saying is that , um ,
you know , if I had a penis ,
I would have been bitten years ago .
I may have to penalize you .
Perhaps another couple of years . Perhaps 10 years . Hmm ?
Like one big circle just biting each other 's dicks .
They don 't even wear shirts . They wear blouses .
It 's just this big homoerotic dick-biting club ,
and I 'm stuck here ironing their fuckin ' frills .
Also clean the bathroom , please .
There 's blood everywhere . It is gruesome .
DEACON : Okay , see you tomorrow .
Off to bed , please .
VIAGO : Katherine .
She was so charming and nice . She was everything I wanted .
Unfortunately , ja , she was married .
Sure , I wanted to kill the guy .
I thought about chopping his head off ,
draining him of every drop of blood that he had .
Who wouldn 't ?
But then I also saw how happy she was ,
and that made me kind of happy .
And I didn 't want to ruin it for her ,
so I did the honorable thing ,
and I just stepped back , and let her live her life .
( CREAKING )
( RHYTHMIC THUDDING )
( PETYR SCREAMING )
DEACON : What ?
VIAGO : Petyr !
Petyr !
Where is it ? Petyr !
DEACON : Petyr ! VIAGO : Petyr !
( SCREAMING )
Petyr ! Get water !
Petyr , get out of the sunlight .
Water ! Get water !
- Get water ! - Petyr , get away from the sunlight .
Get in the shadows . Petyr , get out of the sunlight .
( SCREAMING ) Get out of my way !
DEACON : I 'm going in ! VIAGO : No .
I 'm coming , Petyr !
- Deacon , no , it 's sunlight ! - I 'm coming for you !
It 's sunlight out there !
VIAGO : It 's sunlight ! It 's sunlight !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
I was too late .
( VIAGO SOBBING )
VLADISLAV : Turn that thing off .
Our friend has just been killed
in a fatal sunlight accident .
DEACON : So this is what I think happened .
The Vampire Hunter has broken through the window here ,
has impacted the table , breaking the table leg .
Then he has come this way ,
towards the tomb .
( GAGGING )
DEACON : Crucifix ! Cover the crucifix !
And then Petyr has burst from the tomb ,
pushed the tomb lid onto the Vampire Hunter ,
and then the sunlight has come through here
and burned Petyr alive .
I think this is just a table leg , which is sanded down .
Do you think he hand-sanded that or ...
- Yes . Imagine that stuck in your ... - Your leg .
VIAGO : It 's quite shocking down here , Nick .
Look , here 's our sweet Petyr
- burned to a sizzle . - NICK : Oh ! Fuck . Yeah .
VLADISLAV : I can 't figure out this .
This is the Vampire Hunter .
- Is this his front or his back ? - NICK : Oh , who 's this guy ?
VIAGO : Look at his bloody head on back-to-front .
Twist it the other way , the other way .
VLADISLAV : This way .
VIAGO : See who this guy is here .
- Hmm . Typical macho type . - Yuck !
Hideous .
NICK : Oh , shit .
I know that guy , actually .
VLADISLAV : You know him ?
- Yeah . - VIAGO : What ?
I saw him the other night in town .
- Told him I was a vampire . - VIAGO : What ?
I thought he was joking . He said he was a vampire hunter .
You let a vampire hunter into our house ?
I didn 't let him in . I just gave him my email .
- He didn 't ... - VIAGO : Nick !
I will tear out your tongue
- and shove it down your ass ! - NICK : Deacon ...
VIAGO : Guys ...
( DEACON SNARLING )
NICK : Fucking hell !
DEACON : I 'm going to kill you !
( DEACON GRUNTING )
Tear out your tongue !
DEACON : You kill Petyr with your big mouth !
NICK : It was a mistake !
Get up . Take a breath .
DEACON : Get up and stand on this ceiling like a man .
( GRUNTING )
- ( SNARLING ) - ( HISSING )
We can talk about this , okay ? We can talk about it .
DEACON : I 'll kill you !
I 'm already dead !
NICK : Stu , stay back .
( GROWLING )
- ( KNOCKING ) - ( SHUSHING )
VIAGO : There 's someone at the door .
I 'll go . I 'll go .
Oh , shit .
Yeah , good evening , sir .
Hello , Police .
Hi , I 'm Constable O 'Leary . This is Constable Minogue .
We 're just responding to reports
of a possible forced entry ,
and also a rather large amount of shrieking .
Just wondering if maybe we could come in ,
just have a wee look around .
Okay .
What 's with the ... Hello . What 's with the , um , camera ?
Yeah , obviously we 're just here ' cause there was a phone call from
a member of the public about a bit of a disturbance .
Um ... Some loud noises ,
- possibly a forced entry , wasn 't there ? - Hmm .
And also maybe a bit of smoke coming out .
So we 're just checking over the scene ,
making sure everything 's above board , so to speak ,
and making sure no one 's in danger , that kind of thing .
We might go up and have a wee look up there ,
if that 's all right with you .
- Just part of the job . Yep . - Come on , mate , you lead the way .
Okay .
- Smells a bit weird in here , too , mate . - Yeah .
What do you call that ?
Barbecue .
You will not notice anything out of the ordinary .
No , we certainly hope not .
Let 's just keep going .
POLICEWOMAN : Yeah , hi there , guys . STU : Hello .
- How are you ? - Good .
POLICEMAN : Hey , fellas . VLADISLAV : Hello .
POLICEWOMAN : Is this the room we 've heard all the shouting coming from ?
DEACON : That was me .
POLICEWOMAN : Yeah , okay . We 've had a couple of reports , okay ?
There 's a couple of people not that happy about the level of noise here .
- Okay . The neighbors ? - POLICEMAN : You can 't keep screaming
when there 's this many people around , mate .
You 've got neighbors on either side .
( WHISPERING ) Really nervous .
I 've hypnotized those cops .
I 'm not a great hypnotizer ,
so it could wear off any second .
I really hope that those guys don 't kill those police
because it will mean more police will come ,
possibly even Christians ,
which is totally the last thing we need in this house .
I can see you 're having a good time .
End of the day , we 've got to keep the peace , okay ?
Whoa , whoa , whoa .
See what I 'm seeing ?
POLICEWOMAN : What 's that , Minogue ?
You 're joking .
Not a smoke alarm in sight .
POLICEMAN : No smoke detectors , mate .
Rule number one , smoke detectors .
Okay .
Rule number two , maybe not so many barbecues inside .
- Sort it out , fellas . - DEACON : Okay .
POLICEMAN : Barbecue smells really strong down here , doesn 't it ?
- What kind of marinade ... - Yeah .
What kind of marinade did you use ?
Who 's this guy ?
Um ... That 's a friend who came to our party .
Mate , are you all right ?
- He 's drunk . - That 's what I thought .
- Drunk guy . - Yeah .
Look , you can 't just leave him down here like that , okay ?
This guy 's not having a good time .
He 's gonna feel terrible tomorrow morning .
Well , his soul is in hell , so don 't worry .
Well , I don 't know where his soul is ,
but all I am saying is , where is his blanket ?
Okay , just check on him in the morning .
There 's a big slab of concrete on him .
VIAGO : Yeah . POLICEMAN : You could move that .
That 's definitely not gonna be comfortable .
- See anything else in here , Minogue ? - No , I 've seen enough .
- Okay . - Hang on a minute .
What have we got here ?
POLICEWOMAN : What is that ? VIAGO : This ?
- This ? - Oh , this ?
You can see it as clearly as I can .
Adhesive , mate . That 's a flammable .
Then you 've got a lamp on top of that ,
directly underneath a power source .
That is quite bad , guys .
- It 's very bad . - It 's a very bad combination .
And no smoke detectors again , are there ?
- No . - Yes , there are .
Yes , there are . I see them , yeah . That 's good .
- Lots to think about , guys . - Okay .
Yeah , lots to think about there , guys .
- Well , shall we carry on ? - Next flat meeting . Ja ?
Yeah , good thinking . That 's the thing .
Just have a bit of dialogue about it .
VIAGO : Okay .
They 've got a really good point .
Wait . Let 's kill them .
No .
Well , let 's just see what other safety points they have ,
and then maybe we 'll kill them .
I call into session this trial of Nick of Wellington .
VLADISLAV : Read the charges .
" Problems we have with Nick .
" Number One . "
You brought a human into our house ,
which is a big no-no in the vampire world .
Stu is okay , though ?
Yeah . Stu is fine ,
so I guess we 'll just cross that one out .
Uh ...
VIAGO : Thank you , Stu . VLADISLAV : Thank you , Stu .
VIAGO : So , the new Number One .
" Nick 's been telling people he 's a vampire .
" That , in turn , resulted
" in an unwanted visit from a vampire hunter .
" Crime Number Two . "
This is quite a biggie , Nick .
The Vampire Hunter who killed Petyr .
That actually should 've ...
That should 've been Crime Number One ,
but we wanted to build up to that .
Number Three ,
Deacon doesn 't like that you wear
the same jacket as him ,
and he would like you to find your own original style .
For these crimes of which , we , the Vampire Council , find you guilty ,
you shall be banished from our flat indefinitely .
- Indefinitely . - Indefinitely .
So I can come back ?
No , no . " Indefinitely " means there is no end .
- I thought it was like ... - I just think it ...
VIAGO : No , " indefinite " means that it 's not
a definite thing , it can be changed .
- Does it , though ? - Yes , but it 's long .
It could be tomorrow , it could be six months .
- No , it is not tomorrow . - No , it won 't be tomorrow .
- Forget about it . You 're banished . - It 's at least six months .
- You 're banished . - That 's it .
VLADISLAV : But , Stu , you can visit if you like .
Thank you .
DEACON : For your crimes , you will be made to suffer
the Procession of Shame .
I asked them , Nick . I asked them not to pass that sentence .
We should do this immediately , in my opinion .
You didn 't ask .
You didn 't ask . You were saying yes .
- I didn 't . Well , I ... - Well , this is what 's going to happen .
I still think it 's quite extreme .
Let us do the Procession of Shame now .
VLADISLAV : Shame . DEACON : Shame .
VIAGO : Shame . Shame . Shame .
VLADISLAV : Shame . Shame . Shame .
DEACON : Shame !
VIAGO : Bad vampire ! DEACON : Shame .
VLADISLAV : Shame .
Should we go , Stu ?
VIAGO : ( WHISPERS ) Bye , Stu .
( GATE CREAKING )
VLADISLAV : That was a shame .
( SIGHING )
DEACON : So today we have an invitation
to the big event of the year .
VIAGO : Breaking it open .
DEACON : They have burned the edges .
VIAGO : Like a treasure map or something .
VLADISLAV : It looks very authentic , doesn 't it ?
" Dearly departed ... "
That 's us .
" The Wellington Vampire Association
" in conjunction with the Lower Hutt Vampire Witch Club
" and the Karori Zombie Society
" invites you to attend The Unholy Masquerade
" on the night of the 6th of June ,
" starting at 6 : 00 p.m. "
666 .
Oh , yeah .
VLADISLAV : The Unholy Masquerade , of course ,
is great time for the undead community of Wellington .
There 's zombies there ,
vampires , banshees , all having a dance together .
It 's always a big deal for me .
Love it .
One year I went to The Unholy Masquerade
dressed as Whoopi Goldberg
from Sister Act 1 and Sister Act 2 : Back in the Habit .
It didn 't go down so well because she was a nun .
We vampires don 't like nuns .
VLADISLAV : Of course the big deal of The Unholy Masquerade is ,
every year they announce a Guest of Honor .
And I don 't know if I should be saying this ,
but I heard a little rumor
that the Guest of Honor this year
might be me .
DEACON : The location ...
VLADISLAV : Oh , where ? Yeah , where is it ?
Oh , the location .
The Cathedral of Despair .
And the Guest of Honor will be ...
Who is it ? Show me .
Mmm .
VLADISLAV : ( SIGHING ) Okay . Okay .
Okay . Okay , that 's fine . That 's fine .
Okay ?
( VLADISLAV SHOUTING )
I can 't believe it !
( CRASHING )
Vladislav has
just had a reaction to the information
that the Guest of Honor will be , um ...
The Beast .
The darkest part of my mind is reserved for The Beast .
We could tell you a thing or two about The Beast .
You should pray that you never have to see The Beast .
This one is called The Beast .
And I said , " Get your hands off my balls , Beast ! "
He may have told you some stories
about his great battle with The Beast .
Yeah . " Oh , I fought The Beast on a cliff .
" Oh , I fought The Beast in a swamp .
" And then one time I fought The Beast
" in the toilets of a nightclub . "
Difficult battle .
I hope you never see The Beast .
The Beast .
You can 't go to the ball as Blade . He 's a vampire hunter .
VIAGO : Yeah , but vampires love Wesley Snipes , so it 's ...
No , it 's inappropriate .
Okay , Vlad , the green jodhpurs
or the black leather with the dragon belt ?
I 'm having a mild crisis here .
Just wear the pants you 're going to wear .
Which pants do you want to wear ?
Just look at the pants , Vlad . Turn around and look at them .
They 're just pants !
- Shit , man ! - Holy shit !
VIAGO : Oh , you look terrible .
The black pants .
Thank you . Get dressed .
I don 't know if I feel up to it , really .
VIAGO : You don 't look that great ,
but if you eat someone on the way
- and rejuvenate a little bit ... - I 'm fine . I just ...
You could probably wear a mask or something .
Just leave me to do my dark bidding on the Internet .
What are you bidding on ?
I 'm bidding on a table .
- Are you coming or not ? - Not .
VIAGO : I 'm gonna go change . We 're leaving in 10 minutes .
( SIGHS )
Have a good time .
( TANGO MUSIC PLAYING )
- Hello . - Great !
We tend to often , you know ,
without getting into that kind of ( GROANING ) stuff .
Which I 'm really sick of that . But , you know , it 's just ,
it 's harder for us to actually chase people down .
Can I introduce Gary and Alicia ? They 're ...
( BOTH GROANING )
- Hi , how are you ? - Hi there .
- Hi , how 's it going ? - ( STUTTERS )
Less groaning . Less groaning , guys .
So we are at The Unholy Masquerade .
It 's great . This is my mask ,
which I made for the occasion .
- Ah ! ( LAUGHING ) - Hey !
- Jackie . - Yeah .
This is undead party .
Yeah , I 'm a vampire .
- You 'll have your ... - I 'm a vampire .
I 'm a vampire .
- Great . - Yeah , yeah .
So , um , who bit you ?
Oh , Nick .
- Oh , great . - Yeah .
DEACON : Right , okay .
Deacon !
It 's pretty rude because she was my servant .
She was a pretty useless servant . I wouldn 't worry about it .
DEACON : Yes , but still .
I would 've been appreciated if you had asked .
- Unlike some of these people . - How 's Stu ?
- Stu 's good . He 's there . - Oh , he 's here .
- Stu ! - Stu !
- Hi ! - Hey , hey !
- How are you ? - Hey .
( ALL CHUCKLING )
Has anyone looked at you like they want to eat you at all ?
- Uh , no . - ( MICROPHONE FEEDBACK )
VAMPIRE WITCH : Can you hear me at the back ?
On behalf of the Wellington Vampire Society ,
uh , the Lower Hutt Vampire and Witch Club ,
and the Karori Zombie Society ,
we welcome you here tonight .
We 're raffling a live meat pack this year .
You can inspect the prize over here to my left .
( CROWD MURMURING )
- It 's a wonderful prize . - MAN : No , wait a minute .
Tickets are only $ 10 each , or $ 45 for a book of five .
Now , without further ado , it 's my very great pleasure
to introduce to you this year 's Guest of Honor ,
Pauline Ivanovich .
( CHEERING )
Thank you .
That 's The Beast .
Thank you . Thank you . Thank you .
The Beast is the name I give to my ex-girlfriend , Pauline .
She prefers Pauline .
We had a very intense relationship .
We were very sexually explosive .
Last time I saw her , she impaled me and called me an asshole .
She said all kinds of things that really hurt me ,
and all this while I was impaled on a lamppost .
Well , everyone , I will be mingling around ,
and I really hope that I will meet
all of you .
( SCATTERED APPLAUSE )
( UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING )
Hello .
VIAGO : That 's the new guy .
Do you know what kind of vampire he is ?
- If he is a vampire . - DEACON : Did you see his face ?
Hello .
Oh . Oh .
- Hello . - VIAGO : Hi , how are you ?
This is Deacon .
Hello , Deacon .
- This is Stu , our friend . - Stu ?
G 'day , Stu . How are you , mate ?
- ( GASPS ) Whoa . - Good .
- Hi . Stu . - Stu . Julian , hello .
You 've got really warm hands , Stu .
Are you a demon ?
- No , he 's not a demon . - No , no .
I 'm a software analyst . I ...
- Hey , Stu , Stu ... - A male witch ?
- You 're a male witch . - It 's kind of a technical ...
Stu , you should go dance , um , with anyone .
- Sure . - Okay , take your time .
I like Stu . He 's not vampire , so he ... What , he 's a zombie or ...
Male witch ?
He 's not , uh ... He 's neither . He 's more of a human .
Excuse me . Excuse me . Hi .
Nick , hey . Nick ...
Do you mind if Stu is killed ?
Uh , I don 't feel that good about it .
( STAMMERING ) Can I just ask you a personal question ?
- Sure . - Are you , um ...
Are you pre-deceased ?
Uh ...
If anyone 's gonna eat him , it 's gonna be us , but we 're not ...
We 're past that .
They can just go fuck themselves .
Nick , it is your fault , okay ?
You brought a human into this den of vampiressness .
- What , a plus one ? - You 're not helping .
- Yes , you did . - My plus one .
Lovely talking to you . I 've got to shoot off now .
See you later on .
( SNIFFING AND GROANING )
As soon as one vampire takes a bite ,
- it 's a blood frenzy . - Frenzy !
Okay , we 've got to get him out .
Okay , let 's go .
- Okay , follow me , follow me . - VIAGO : Excuse me . Sorry , guys .
Okay , Stu , put that over your bloody red face .
- Just going out . - NICK : Going outside for a cigarette .
DEACON : Oh , hey .
Okay , not that way . Not that way .
This way . This way .
Is there another way ? Oh .
- DEACON : Not this way . - ( PAULINE LAUGHING )
- Back away from the vampires . - Guys ...
PAULINE : Excuse me , everyone !
Can I have your attention , please ?
Some of the vampires forget Unholy Masquerade rules .
They brought a human ...
( CROWD MURMURING AND HISSING )
... and they don 't let us to feast on him .
( HISSES AND LAUGHS )
This is a total misunderstanding .
There was on the invitation ... And this actually pertains to you .
The invitation , it said , " Plus one , "
- but it did not specify ... - Hey , mate . Look ...
If it could be a human , or if it could be a werewolf .
Yeah , but you could be a vampire hunter for all we 'd know .
He could be texting his mates saying ,
" I 've got them all in the one place .
" Come on over and we 'll have a vampire barbecue . "
- ( CROWD LAUGHS ) - Well , he 's not . He 's not doing that .
Well , we don 't know that , do we ? How do we know that ?
He 's wearing a bowtie . Look at him !
Stu , tell them what you do .
Come on , Stu . Tell us what you do .
- Come on , Stu . - Tell them what you do , Stu .
- Uh , hi , my name is Stu . I 'm a ... - Don 't fuck it up .
- PAULINE : I can 't hear , Stu . - Louder , louder .
Uh , hi , my name is Stu . Um , I work in IT .
- I can 't hear . - Louder .
Speak up , Stu . They can 't hear you . They cannot hear you .
Hi , my name is Stu . Uh , I 'm a software analyst .
I work for a geographic information systems company .
PAULINE : Sorry , what is it ?
STU : I work for a company that does , um ...
Basically , we take , like , business requirements from organizations ,
and we , um , analyze those requirements ,
and then we build software to fit those requirements .
He is a virgin . He is a virgin .
I can smell a virgin at a thousand paces .
Go on then . Go a thousand paces away and smell yourself .
( HISSING )
- ( CROWD HISSING ) - I can 't wait anymore .
( LAUGHING )
VLADISLAV : No !
( HISSES )
There shall be no eating of the human .
Who are you all of a sudden ?
You have forgotten your former lover so quickly .
Georgie ?
No , not Georgie . Like , five years after .
Wait a minute . Just one moment .
( WHISPERS ) Viago ...
No , I 've got it . That 's got it . Takes away from ...
( GASPS )
Hello , Beast .
Hello , asshole .
Hey , don 't call me asshole .
Don 't call me Beast .
- This is Vladislav . - Yes , they 're absolutely the same .
This is my ex-boyfriend . You know , the one who fucked that witch ?
All right . That 's old business . That 's personal business .
Nice to meet you , asshole .
This is my lover .
You will not feast on the blood of the human known as Stu .
Listen , asshole , this is human and this is the rules .
And what is cameras doing here ?
One , then another one . What is this ?
We 're making a documentary on ...
JULIAN : This is a private secret society , mate .
Exactly .
JULIAN : You don 't go bringing your bloody cameras into everything .
You will not eat Stu , and you will not eat the camera guy .
Maybe one camera guy ...
I 'm up to about bloody here with you at the moment .
And all your mates behind there , whoever the hell they are .
We 're gonna eat the human being ,
and there 's nothing you can do about it , all right ?
Now back off and let my missus get her way .
Oh , there 's nothing I can do about it ?
- JULIAN : That 's right , mate . - Well , what about this ?
( GRUNTS )
PAULINE : Rip his head off .
What do you want ?
VIAGO : Vampire fight !
Get him , Vladislav .
( CHEERING )
( BOTH SCREAMING )
PAULINE : Rip his head off !
( BOTH GRUNTING )
VIAGO : He 's killing him !
It is forbidden for vampires to kill vampires .
- ( THUD ) - ( GROANING )
What the ...
PAULINE : Vlad ! Oh !
What ?
- Are you okay , love ? Get out ! - ( GROANING )
We should probably go , Stu .
It was great to see you , Pauline .
Asshole !
- Bastards ! - VIAGO : Yeah , Stu .
VLADISLAV : That was great how we both ...
He 's a murderer .
We both together equally destroyed that guy .
Yeah , but it was more Stu with the giant stick .
I hope this doesn 't make it awkward for you and The Beast .
No , I think it 's opened up new possibilities .
Oh , no .
- Here we go again . - ( SIGHS ) Here we go again .
( ALL SINGING ) Stu , Stu , Stu , Stu ! Stu , Stu , Stu !
Stu , Stu , Stu , Stu , Stu , Stu ...
Wait , wait , wait , wait , stop ! Listen , listen ! ( SNIFFS )
You smell that ?
( SNIFFING )
This way .
Werewolves .
ANTON : Oh , no .
DEACON : Look what the cat dragged in , huh .
CLIFTON : Piss off .
ANTON : Keep walking . Don 't hassle us tonight .
VLADISLAV : There has been no hassle here .
Well , let it stay that way . Keep chaining yourselves up .
Guys , where 's your tracksuit pants ?
It was , um , washing night .
My missus couldn 't wash them
' cause there was too much blood on them . So ...
When your legs expand , they grow into the tracksuit .
CLIFTON : Oh .
Those jeans are gonna rip completely .
You 've lost all those trousers , guys .
Declan , that tree is far too thin .
Look at it . It 's like a branch .
You know how big you get when you transform .
That 's the wrong tree for you .
Anton , I 've ...
Oh , no , you 've forgotten the combination .
Why did you get a combination lock ?
I lost my key last time .
ANTON : Okay , well , it 's probably 4 zeros .
That 's the factory setting , is it ?
Fuck off to a tree .
CLIFTON : Hey ! Werewolves , not swear-wolves .
ANTON : Yeah , I know . But on transformation nights it 's all right .
All right ? I 'm getting stressed out .
CLIFTON : I was just reminding you .
ANTON : Stop talking and chain yourself up , you dickhead !
Honestly , we 're transforming .
VLADISLAV : All right , we 'll keep walking .
- Yeah , keep walking . - Well , we 're walking .
By the way , I find that offensive .
Is it fur ?
ANTON : Oh , for crying out loud .
Don 't look at the fur , everyone . Get back to your trees , okay ?
- That 's disgusting , man . - VLADISLAV : You 're wearing fur .
ANTON : Declan ! DECLAN : Anton !
- CLIFTON : That 's not real fur . - Oh , shit !
( WEREWOLVES GROWLING AND SNARLING )
Right .
Honestly , get out of here . Take your humans !
The guy in the bowtie , he 's gonna go first !
Camera crew , get out of here !
Quick ! Take all your clothes off
that you want to keep , everyone !
Get that army surplus jacket off .
You 've only just bought that , Nathan .
( GROWLING )
WEREWOLF : Get that camera out of my face !
VIAGO : Guys , guys , guys . Let 's go . Let 's go . Come on !
( GROWLING )
VIAGO : Run , Stu ! Run ! No !
Let 's go , let 's go !
DEACON : They 're coming , guys ! VIAGO : Shit !
DEACON : I got one !
- ( GRUNTING ) - ( GROWLING )
( CAMERAMAN RUNNING AND BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GROWLING )
( SCREAMING )
CAMERAMAN : My leg ! My leg !
NICK : Oh , God !
Stu ! Stu !
- ( STU SCREAMING ) - Stu !
( STU YELLING )
Stu !
( STU GROANING )
STU : Get away ! Argh !
- NICK : Stu , are you all right ? - ( STU SCREAMING )
Whoa ! Whoa ! Whoa !
Stu !
Fuck off , asshole !
Fuck off !
( GROWLING )
Fuck off ! Get off , dick !
You stinking gang of assholes !
( WEREWOLVES SNARLING AND GROWLING )
No , no , no , no . Whoa ! Whoa ! Whoa !
DEACON : Stupid werewolves !
Look away , Nick ! Don 't look at the blood !
No , Stu ! Stu !
He was a really good dude . Leave him alone !
DEACON : It 's too late for him !
Don 't look at the blood , Nick .
NICK : Stu !
( HOWLING )
( MELANCHOLY MUSIC )
( LEAVES RUSTLING )
There he is .
He 's probably still a little upset ,
having seen his best friend disemboweled by werewolves .
Nick , I found you .
Whoa .
That was pretty full-on , eh .
( BREATHES DEEPLY )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
But this is what happens when you are a vampire .
You have to watch everyone die .
Your mother and father . All your friends .
Sometimes brutal .
Like slipping and falling onto a giant spike ,
or falling asleep in an autumn pile of leaves
and having some of them block your windpipe .
Or making the simple mistake of fashioning a mask out of crackers ,
and being attacked by ducks , geese , swans .
Or simply dying of old age .
But even old age is brutal .
Watching your friends grow old .
They can 't piss .
And they say stupid things , and their brains go ,
and they can 't remember anything .
And then , one day , they can 't even remember who you are .
And you wish they were dead .
And then they do die .
( SIGHS HEAVILY )
No . If I know Stu ,
this was probably the way he wanted to go .
Disemboweled by werewolves .
Blood and guts splayed onto the trees .
His face torn to shreds .
( SIGHS )
I hope I made you feel better .
POLICEWOMAN : Uh , well , from what we can see and what we can gather ,
it looks like there 's been a bit of a dog attack .
That 's really what happens when you get , you know , dangerous dogs
out on the streets , not being looked after .
This is not good .
No , not good at all .
POLICEMAN : There 's nicer ways to go than being torn apart by , uh ,
what looks like a pack of dogs .
- More than just one . - POLICEWOMAN : Yeah , I 'd say so .
These attacks are becoming more and more frequent .
They 're happening on a monthly basis , and it 's just ...
It 's no good for anybody , okay ?
Especially not the dogs . Certainly not the community .
Here , O 'Leary . I got the bastard . One of them here .
And that 's what I 'm talking about . Look at it .
End of the day , this dog is gonna have to be put down .
- What a shame . - ( DOG WHINES )
Look what you did . Eh ?
Now , he 's got the scent again , hasn 't he ?
He wants to go again . He 's not finished .
POLICEWOMAN : Yeah .
VIAGO : They say that vampires ' hearts are cold and dead .
Definitely dead .
NICK : Bye , Stu .
VLADISLAV : He would 've loved this scarf .
DEACON : It 's a lovely loose knit .
VIAGO : But I don 't know . I think I still feel things inside it .
Deacon !
Deacon , wakey-wakey . Hey .
Viago ...
You were asleep in here with the curtains open . It 's nearly morning .
- Oh . - You want to get sizzled to a crisp ?
You know you 've got to think a little bit about these things .
Okay . Sorry , Viago .
No , it 's okay .
- Night-night . - Night-night . Okay .
VOICEMAIL : Received at 4 : 20 a.m.
( NICK ON VOICEMAIL )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
( LINE BEEPS )
( KNOCKING CONTINUES )
Ah !
- Stu ! - Hey , Deacon .
- Stu ! ( LAUGHS ) - How 's it ?
Good to see you .
Look at his face .
I saw them tear you to shreds .
Look , he looks like Seal .
They didn 't kill me .
It looks cool .
Thank you , thank you .
Meet some of our friends .
Anton ...
Deacon . Hi , Anton .
Anton .
( SNIFFING )
I must have blacked out .
And then I remember an ambulance .
POLICEMAN : He 's going into shock , O 'Leary !
- Yeah , yeah . I 'm on it . - O 'Leary !
Yeah , coming .
- ( GROWLING ) - Okay . Just calm down , mate .
Calm down . Grab his legs !
POLICEWOMAN : Just hang on a moment .
( STU SNARLING )
POLICEMAN : Looks like rabies , doesn 't it ?
STU : And I don 't know how long after that it was ,
but I , like , woke up and it was daytime .
And I couldn 't find my clothes .
Those werewolf guys , um , eventually found me ,
and they had some ... They lent me some pants .
So , yeah , those guys have been supporting me ,
' cause I was quite confused .
Yeah , these are the guys who turned me into a werewolf .
( SNIFFING )
CLIFTON : Did you knit your own jersey ?
- Yes . - CLIFTON : Oh , yeah .
- I knit . - Is that the moon , or ...
Yes .
Hopefully , we won 't , you know ... ( GROWLS )
( ALL LAUGHING )
Oh , this is a nice place .
DEACON : Please , don 't lick anything or pee on anything .
We were worried at first , you know .
We thought , " Oh , they 're just going to urinate on everything . "
But they 're actually really polite and pretty clean .
( ALL CHEERING )
There was obviously that werewolf smell ,
which permeated the entire house for the first half an hour .
But we opened some windows and got rid of that .
ANTON : When Stu first suggested the idea ,
I thought , " No way . You know ,
" walking into the vampires ' den . That 's ludicrous . "
WEREWOLF : That 's my hand .
But I thought , " Well , we 'll give it a shot . "
You know , I mean , I 'm the alpha male , so I made the call .
- I 'm the alpha male . - Yes .
So , generally , all the other guys follow me .
VLADISLAV : To Stu ! ALL : To Stu !
Thanks , guys .
What have you done to your face ?
I got attacked by some werewolves .
Ooh , I met a werewolf . Seemed a very nice person .
So Katherine is a vampire now .
Yes .
Yeah , we decided to get together .
We just thought , " To hell with it , " you know ?
" What have we got to lose ? "
KATHERINE : I was just sitting , doing nothing ,
and he came floating in and over to me ,
and I recognized him . It was wonderful .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
That 's right . I bit you on the neck .
That 's right .
And I don 't mind being a vampire .
I 'm enjoying it .
VIAGO : Some people freak out a bit about the age difference .
They think , " What 's this 96-year-old lady doing
" with a guy four times her age ? "
And , you know , I don 't care .
It doesn 't make any difference .
No , they can call me " cradle-snatcher . " Who cares ?
I decided to bite her , and we 're gonna be together forever .
- Wonderful . - Yeah .
VLADISLAV : Pauline and I are tentatively back together .
But it 's not long before you remember
why it was you broke up in the first place .
( VLADISLAV SCREAMING AND GRUNTING )
( VLADISLAV SPEAKING GERMAN )
( PAULINE SPEAKING GERMAN )
JACKIE : We 'll start in our bedroom .
I need it totally boarded up or blacked out somehow .
My husband is my familiar ,
so there has been a dynamic shift there .
You could buy a BeDazzler . So write that down .
- Yeah . - Because ... That 's B-E-D ...
I feel like I 'm who I 'm really meant to be now .
- JACKIE : I love you . - I love you , too .
Great .
But I am your master .
- Okay ? - Yeah .
Yeah , these guys have to laugh at my jokes . Right , guys ?
WEREWOLVES : Yeah .
That is a good one , man .
I always look round and make sure they 're all laughing .
If I see one of them is not quite laughing ,
I 'll go , " Hey . Are you laughing ? "
And then often I 'll test you . What were you laughing at , Clifton ?
- Eh ? - What are you laughing at now ?
- Just then ? - Yeah , but what ?
Oh , I don 't know , ' cause you ...
Oh , test failed ! Test failed ! Yeah !
( ALL SHOUTING AND LAUGHING )
You 're laughing now . What are you laughing at now , though ?
I don 't know ' cause ...
- Oh , another failure ! - ( ALL LAUGHING )
Well , what are you laughing at , Stu ?
I was laughing with the group .
Yep . That 's good . That 's good . Yeah , he 's in . See ? Yeah .
Just pay attention . Pay attention .
Laugh with the group .
You will not remember the last hour and a half
of what you have just seen .
You will forget the contents of this movie .
( SNAPS FINGERS )